Samanway **Ghatak**

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

26/3, Sastri Narendra Nath Ganguly Road, Howrah, West Bengal, India

🛘 (+91) 98-749-89959 | 🗖 samanway.ghatak@gmail.com | 🎢 devil1993.github.io | 🖸 https://github.com/devil1993 | 🖹 SamGhatak | 🗖 Samanway Ghatak

Summary_

Current Software Architect at Enterprise Content Management Software development organization Hyland. 8+ years experience in full stack development, software design, software maintenance and mentoring junior developers to write well designed maintainable code. Interested in machine learning, genetic algorithms and blockchain technologies.

Work Experience _____

Hyland Kolkata, India

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

August 2019 - Present

- Joined as Developer 3 (Senior Developer) in August 2019 and got promoted to Software Architect 3 (Team level Architect) in June 2021
- TaskList: Designed and developed a deficiency management application for medical records management and workflows.
- PKPhysicianValidator and PKBFF: Designed and developed 2 backward compatible application to support PatientKeeper (A third party health-care application for physicians) integration with OnBase.
- Worked on numerous 3rd party dependency vulnerabilities as developer to provide secure software. One of this included migrating a java web application developed with Axis 1.x to CXFs
- Developed a patch deployment feature of OneContent Suite of application that enables administrators from the customer sites to deploy quick fixes and patches without involvement of the services or development team.
- Worked on different innovation ideas as part of Hyland Labs initiatives and hackathons.

Factset Systems India Hyderabad, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2

July 2018 - August 2019

- · Joined as Software Engineer in July 2018 and got promoted to Software Engineer 2 in April 2019.
- Worked on an enterprise calculation engine for fixed income securities. Primarily worked on adding support for a new type of security analysis that was not supported by the engine earlier. Primary technology used was C++ along with occasional use of python.
- Enhanced and maintained a web based application used by the product development team. Delivered long desired feature by tweaking the underlying framework code. Primary technology used: C# and Ext.Js
- Developed a analysis tool that deals with a large data set and runs some statistical measures on the data. Used by internal product developers to analyze and calibrate the impact of re-engineering done by development teams.
- · Maintained and enhanced internal tool highly used by the financial analysis teams for running security analysis daily.

National Institute of Technology, Durgapur

Durgapur, India

TEACHING ASSISTANCE

August 2016 - July 2018

- Had the role of teaching assistance as a part of the masters curriculum.
- Teached and mentored junior undergrad students on basic computation, C Programming, Object Oriented Programming with C++
- Setting up questions and conducting lab examinations

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Hyderabad and Kolkata, India

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

June 2014 - August 2016

- Worked on re-engineering of a leading assessment platform for Cambridge Assessment one of the largest assessment agencies to increase the supported load from 100 concurrent users to 4000 concurrent users.
- $\bullet \ \ Worked\ as\ a\ full\ stack\ developer\ with\ primary\ technologies\ being\ C\#\ and\ j\ Query.\ Frameworks\ used\ -\ WCF,\ MVC,\ Dapper,\ Redis,\ Enterprise\ Library\ Bernoul C\#\ and\ primary\ being\ C\#\ and\ prima$

Education

National Institute of Technology, Durgapur

Jalpaiguri Govenrment Engineering College

Durgapur, West Bengal, India

M.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

August 2016 - August 2018

• Gold medalist with GPA - 9.12

Jalpaiguri, West Bengal, India

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

July 2010 - June 2014

D. FECH IN COMPOTER SCIENCE AND ENGINE

Secured GPA - 8.18

Howrah Vivekananda Institution

Howrah, West Bengal, India

HIGHER SECONDARY EDUCATION IN SCIENCE

2008 - 2010

· Secured 90.2% in Higher Secondary Examination conducted by West Bengal Council for Higher Secondary Education

Howrah Vivekananda Institution

Howrah, West Bengal, India

SECONDARY EDUCATION

1998 - 2008

• Secured 93% in Secondary Examination conducted by West Bengal Board of Secondary Education

Honors & Awards

FACTSET

2019 **Star Award**, For performance in 2019

Hyderabad, India

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

2016 **Rising Star Award**, For contributions in 2016

Kolkata, India

Hobbies_

GAMES AND SPORTS

- Playing Cricket, Table Tennis, Volleyball
- Follow other sports like Football, Tennis

MUSIC AND MOVIES

- Playing Drums and Guitar.
- Love listening to different genres of music.
- Like watching thrillers.